Inventory of the Jerdone Family Papers 1753-1890, 1771-1845
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Jerdone Family Papers, 1753-1890, 1771-1845.
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 39.1 J47
2,672 items.
Includes letters, letterbooks, and account books of immigrant Francis Jerdone merchant of Yorktown, Virginia; and Hanover County, Virginia. Most of the collection consists of letters, accounts and diaries of the next two generations of members of the Jerdone family, including Francis Jerdone and his sons John, Francis and William Jerdone. The papers concern the management of two estates "Providence Forge," New Kent County, Virginia and "Mount Sterling," Charles City County, Virginia.
Jerdone Family;; Francis Jerdone, 1721-1771;; Francis Jerdone, 1756-1841;; Francis Jerdone, b. 1802;; John Jerdone;; William Jerdone;; Thomas Jett;; John Morton Jordan & Co. (London, England).
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Purchased: 1,784 items.
Purchased: 389 items, 04/24/1939.
Purchased: 407 items, 01/29/1940.
Gift: 34 items, 07/10/1963.
Gift: 16 items, 12/09/1964.
Acc. No. 76-4; Gift: 5 items, 02/01/1976.
Gift: 3 items, 10/01/1976.
Gift: 1 items, 11/01/1976.
Acc. No. 77-30; Gift: 1 items, 10/01/1977.
Acc. No. 78-6; Purchased: 19 items, 01/01/1978.
Acc. No. 83-64; Gift: 1 items, 12/01/1983.
Acc. No. 84-26; Gift: 3 items, 04/01/1984.
Acc. No. Sm. Coll. Add. 17; 4 items.
Acc. No. 97-45; Purchased: 3 items, 08/07/1997.
Acc. No. 98.7; Gift: 2 items, 03/06/1998.
Biographical/Historical Information
Francis Jerdone (1721-1771)
Francis Jerdone (1721-1771) was born in Jedbury, Scotland, the son of John Jerdone, a magistrate and treasurer of the town. At the age of nineteen, 1752, he immigrated to Virginia from Scotland and settled in Hanover County, Yorktown; and Louisa County. He made his living as a merchant (factor), running a mercantile business with George Pottie until his death in 1771. Francis Jerdone (1721-1777) married Sarah (Macon) Jerdone (1732-1818) in 1753. The couple had several children including; Mary Jerdone Pottie (1754-1837); Francis Jerdone (1756-1841); Sarah Jerdone Braikenridge (1757-1793); Elizabeth Jerdone Macaulay (1759-1830); Isabella Jerdone Mitchell (1761-1825); Anne Jerdone Thompson (1763-1794); John Jerdone (1764-1786); Martha Jerdone (b. 1767) who died in infancy; and William Jerdone (1769-1772).
Children of Francis Jerdone(1721-1771)
Mary Jerdone Pottie(1754-1837) married George Pottie, a business partner of her father's. Mary helped run this business after her father's death in 1771. They had three children; George Pottie, Isbella Pottie and Mary Pottie Honeyman. Mary Jerdone Pottie later remarried to Adam Toler. They had several children, including; Sarah Toler, Adam Toler, Elizabeth Toler, and William Toler.
Francis Jerdone (1756-1841) made his living as a farmer. He married Polly (Mary) Byars Jerdone (1781-1821) in 1799. The couple had four children who survived infancy; John Jerdone (b. 1800) who married Barbara Callis Jerdone; Francis Jerdone (b. 1802) who married Eliza Watkins Jerdone; William Jerdone (1805-1865) who married Anna Burfitt Jerdone; and Sarah Jerdone Coleman (1807-1863) who married General Clayton G. Coleman. The family were absentee landowners of "Providence Forge," New Kent County and "Mount Sterling,"Charles City County. Eventually William Jerdone would reside at "Mount Sterling."
Sarah Jerdone Braikenridge (1757-1793) married George Braikenridge. They had five children; George Weare Braikenridge (b. 1780), Sarah Braikenridge, Maria Braikenridge, John Braikenridge, and William Braikenridge.
Elizabeth Jerdone Macaulay (1759-1830) married Alexander Macaulay (1745-1798) in 1782. They had six children; Helen Macaulay (b. 1784) who married Peyton Southall in 1802 and Robert Anderson in 1814; Alexander Macaulay (b. 1787); Sally Macaulay (1789)who died in infancy; John Macaulay (1791-1795); Francis Macaulay (1793-1811); and Patrick Macaulay (b. 1795).
Isabella Jerdone Mitchell (1761-1825) married William Mitchell (d. 1816) in 1783. They had three children; William Mitchell; Sarah Mitchell Thompson (1785-1831) who married Garland Thompson (1787-1835) in 1810; and George Mitchell.
Anne Jerdone Thompson (1763-1794) married Charles Thompson (1743-1836) in 1778. They had five children; John Thompson; Garland Thompson (1787-1835) who married Sarah Mitchell Thompson in 1810; Charles Thompson; Francis Thompson; and Sally Thompson.
John Jerdone (1764-1786) spent nine years studying abroad from 1777 until his death in 1786. He studied in England for three years and studied medicine at Edinburgh University in Scotland for six years.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains papers of the Jerdone family, 1753- (1771-1845) -1890. It includes letters, letterbooks, and account books of immigrant Francis Jerdone (1721-1771), Scottish factor who lived in Hanover County, Yorktown and Louisa County, Virginia, and letters of his wife, Sarah (Macon) Jerdone. Most of the collection consists of letters, accounts, and diaries of the next two generations of members of the Jerdone family including Francis Jerdone (1756-1841), planter of Louisa County; his brother John Jerdone (1764-1786); his brother-in-law, Alexander Macaulay of Yorktown, Virginia; and his sons, John Jerdone (b. 1800); Francis Jerdone (b. 1802); and William Jerdone (b. 1805). The letters reflect the daily maintenance of their plantations, "Jerdone Castle" [Louisa County, Virginia], "Providence Forge" [New Kent County, Virginia], "Mount Sterling" [Charles City County, Virginia] and an unnamed plantation in Spotsylvania County, Virginia. The family were absentee owners of "Providence Forge" and "Mount Sterling" and the two estates were managed first by a cousin, William Douglass, and later by hired stewards. (Eventually, William Jerdone lived at "Mount Sterling" and built a brick mansion there.)
The subjects covered in the collection include agriculture, the commission merchant business, the daily routine of men, education, farm management by stewards, and various aspects of slavery. In addition, there are many letters written to Virginia from Scotland and England.
The papers also contain the letterbook of Thomas Jett, Virginia representative of John Morton Jordan and Co., London, England; items from Perkins, Buchanan and Brown, merchants in London, 1769-1776; and documents, 1769-1799, concerning the lawsuit of Jordan v. Skinker.
Arrangement
Organization
This collection is organized into 8 series. Series 1 contains letters; Series 2 contains accounts; Series 3 contains inventories; Series 4 contains legal papers; Series 5 contains miscellaneous material; Series 6 contains manuscript volumes; Series 7 contains artifacts; Series 8 contain additions and accessions to the collection.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by into series. Series 1 is arranged in chronologically order by date and separated into subseries by individual year. The remaining series are primarily arranged chronologically by date.
Additional Related, Separated and Bibliographic Material
Bibliography
Coleman, Sherrard The Will of Francis Jerdone of Louisa County, Virginia, July 10th, 1770. William and Mary Quarterly, 2nd series, XI. 1931: 7-10. Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Jerdone Family. William and Mary Quarterly, 1st series, VI. 1897-1898: 37- 38. Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Letter Book of Francis Jerdone. William and Mary Quarterly, 1st series, IX. 1902-1903: 153-160, 236-242. Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Letter Book of Francis Jerdone. William and Mary Quarterly, 1st series, XIV. 1905-1906: 141-145. Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Null, David Gerard The Library of Francis Jerdone 1978. Master's Thesis, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Call Number: LD6051 .W5m Hist., 1978, N84
Pilaro, Frances Maria The Jerdone Family: Changing Family Relationships in the Early National Period 1988. Honor's Thesis, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Call Number: LD6051 .W5m Hist., 1988, P54
Index to Materials
Staff Prepared Index of Recipients And Selected Subjects in the Letterbook of Francis Jerdone, 1756-1763, Manuscript Volume 9.
Alexander, John n.d. at beginning of book 1756 June 2 1757 January 10 1758 June 10
Arnold, Latham 1756 May 15, June 26 1757 June 27
Bacon, Anthony 1757 May 20 1758 September 8
Boog, Ninlan estate of, is discussed throughout book
Brown, Hugh see Speirs, Alexander & Hugh Brown, merchants, Glasgow, Scotland
Browne, George 1757 June 25 1758 June 10 1759 June 1 1760 September 10 1761 April 28 1762 September 10
Buchanan, James 1761 September 10
Buchanan & Hamilton, bankruptcy of 1756-1757
Buchanan & Simson, Glasgow, Scotland 1762 January 25, August 3, October 10
Buchanan (James) & Company, London, Eng. 1762 December 15
Buckner, Samuel 1759 February 2
Carpice, Joseph 1762 September 20
Caverhill, Thomas, Jedburgh, Scotland 1756 February 10
Chapman, Nathaniel 1759 August 12
Crawfurd, Archibald 1756 June 24, 26 1756 October 4, 8 1757 May 20 1758 October 29 1759 June 26, September 1, November 20 1760 September 10 1761 July 4, September 1 1762 March 10, September 10, October 14, 28
Davidson, John 1756 June 26 1760 September 10 1761 September 1
Dick, Charles, merchant, Fredericksburg, Virginia 1761 January 18
Dunbar, Hancock Copy annexed with letter of Francis Jerdone to Buchanan and Simson, 1762 August 3
Duncanson, Robert, merchant, Fredericksburg, Virginia 1758 February 28
Farell & Jones, Bristol, England 1760 March 10 1761 March 10
Flowerdewe, Thomas 1756 October 4 1757 January 25 1760 July 15, September 10, October 20 1762 September 20
Flowerdewe & Norton 1757 December 5 1758 September 8, October 29 1759 January 20, June 1, 25, September 1, November 20, December 13 1760 April 10 1761 February 20, September 1, 10 1762 March 10, May 1, December 15
Galt, William, Jean Butcher, Robert Moor, Jean Neilson, James Barnhill & Robert Sinclair, Greenock, Scotland 1762 September 10
Gildart, James, Liverpool, England 1761 July 4 1762 September 10
Goore, Charles 1756 June 2
Gordon, Samuel 1759 August 1
Hamilton, William 1756 February 22
Harford, Edward, Jr. 1760 April 10 1761 July 4
Herring, Richard 1761 March 10
Hewitt, Jacob 1759 January 20, September 1 1760 September 10 1762 January 17, September 20
Holden, George, Accomack County, Virginia 1756 June 30
Hunt, Edward 1756 May 15, June 2, June 26 1757 May 10
Hyndman, John 1760 September 10
Jarneson, Dr. Alexander 1760 October 30
Kerr, James 1762 December 4
Knox, Thomas, Bristol, England 1757 February 10 1759 April 20, July 15
Lenox & Scott, Fredericksburg, Virginia 1758 February 28
Lewis, Warner 1760 November 21 1761 February 20 1762 March 10
Lyons, Peter Letter, 1759 September 18, annexed to letter to Samuel Rickards, Israel Maudult & Co.
Mackintosh, Alexander, woolen draper, London, Eng. 1756 June 2 1757 June 25, November 20
Maclane, Duncan, linen draper, London, Eng. 1756 March 4, May 15 1757 January 25, March 10, AprIl 25, June 25 1758 March 1 1759 June 1
Maitland (Robert) and Alexander Maitland, merchants, London, Eng. 1757 September 10 1758 September 8 1759 June 1, 23, December 14 1760 April 30 1761 February 20
Martin, John & Sons 1756 June 26 1759 August 7
Morgan (Thomas) & Company, merchants, Bristol, Eng. 1756 February 10, May 15, June 2, July 8, August 4 1757 February 25, June 16 1757 December 15 1758 February 3, 25 1759 March 5, 8, April 20, June 1
Murray, Alexander 1761 July 4
Murray, James 1760 June 5
Nelson, William 1758 October 28
Norton, John 1757 July 7 1762 February 25
Pendleton, Edmund 1761 July 4
Rickards, Samuel 1756 June 2 1757 March 10, September 10, December 10 1758 September 8 1758 October 29 1759 June 1, September 1, November 22 1760 March 10, September 10, October 20 1761 September 1
Rickards, (Samuel), Israel Maudult & Co. 1756 February 10, 12, June 2, 26, August 4, October 29 1757 March 10, June 16, September 10 1756 June 10, October 29 1759 August 7, November 22 1760 November 1 1761 April 25, 30, September 1, 10 1762 January 30, April 29
Simson, James, merchant, Glasgow, Scotland 1762 January 25, March 5, August 3, October 28
Smith, William 1758 October 29
Speirs, Alexander, late partner of Hugh Brown 1760 May 10, July 15 1761 October 30
Speirs (Alexander) & Hugh Brown, merchants, Glasgow, Scotland 1756 May 15, June 2, August 4, October 25, December 10 1757 February 10, 25; April 25, 28, 29; May 20; June 2, 16, 25; July 2, 25; August 4; September 8, 18; October 25; November 17; December 15 1758 January 10, March 10, April 28, May 8, 18, June 10, August 4, September 15 1759 February 1; March 5; April 4, 22; June 13, 25; August 7; September 4; October 27; November 22
Tait, John 1756 June 26
Tappenden & Hanby, London, Eng. 1756 June 25 1758 September 8
Thomas, Griffiths & Thomas, Bristol, Eng. 1760 May 20, July 15 1761 July 4 1762 September 10 1758 June 10
Thomson, William 1758 June 10
Throckmorton, Mordeca I 1760 May 1
Tucker, John 1759 December 13
Tucker & Bedford, merchants, Barbadoes 1760 October 20 1761 October 24 1762 September 20
Willis, Francis 1759 February 2 1762 March 10
Willis, Francis, Jr. 1760 November 21 1761 February 20 1763 February 25
Willis & Buckner 1762 March 10
Wilson, John, Sr., merchant, Glasgow, Scotland 1761 April 28 1761 July 4
Books listed 1760 September 10
Books ordered for John Carr 1757 January 1
Business, selling of tobacco and the ordering of goods entire book
Church ornaments 1759 January 20 1759 September 1 1760 September 10
Furniture (resting chair) 1759 June 26
French-Indian War 1756 May 15 ff.
Goods ordered from Britain entire book
Poor, Treatment of 1763 March 14
Saddle, description of 1760 March 10 1761 March 10
St. Mark's Parish, Culpeper, Va. 1763 March 14
Slaves, sale of 1762 October 10
Slaves, sale of, in family groups 1760 November 19, 20
Slaves, sale of, splitting of husband and wife 1762 February 25
Tobacco, sale of entire book
Tobacco, switch to broad green from sweet-scented 1758 March 10
Tools 1756 June 25
Virginia, General court 1760 June 5 1761 April 25
Index to Materials
Staff Prepared Index of Recipients in Account And Letterbook, 1738-1744, of William Johnston And Francis Jerdone, Manuscript Volume 8.
Barclay, [?] 1741 July 15
Blake, William 1742 December 1
Bowden, William 1739 July 10 1743 July 1743/44 March 14 1744 May 20, June 12
Buchanan, Neill 1738 October 16, 29; December 2 1738/9 February 27, March 2 1739 April 12; May 7; June 20; July 21; August 8; September 8; ca. September 20; September 20, 22; October 4, 27; November 2; December 14, 22 1739/40 March 10 1740 May 24; June 11; August 25; September 7, 8; November 3 1741 April 18, 23; May 20; July 13; August 5; October 20; November 12 1741/2 January; March 4; April 16; May 20; July 3; August 17; December 1, 10 1742 April 16; May 20; July 3; August 17; December 1; December 10 1743/4 February 4, March 14
Messrs. Buchanan & Wilson (see also next entry of "Messrs. Archi[bal]d Buchanan & John Wilson, Glasgow, Scotland") n.d. [ca. 1739 July 21] 1741 July 13
Messrs. Archi[bal]d Buchanan & John Wilson, Glasgow, Scotland (see also above entry of "Messrs. Buchanan & Wilson") 1739 August 11 n.d., [ca. 1740 June 16) 1740 September 8 1743 June 11 1744 May 21, October 23
Messrs. George Buchanan & William Hamilton, London, Eng. 1744 April 21; May 20; June 12; November 21; December 25 1744/45 January 30
Champion, [?] 1739 April 11
Dabney, Jno. 1738 October 15
Donald, James 1741 July 13
Dunlop, Col. 1741 March 4
Messrs. William Galt, Jean Butcher, Robert Moor, Jean Neilson. James Barnhill & Robert Sinclair, Greenock, Scotland 1762 September 10
Messrs. Gov & Bulkely, Liverpool, Eng. 1743 May 18
Hamilton, W. n.d. [Ca. 1740 September 1]
Hume, James 1739 July 5
Messrs. Edward Main & John Main 1740 April 23
Partridge, Freeman 1738 October 25 1739 July 5, 10, 28; August 12; October 10; December 22 1740 June 16, 28; September 1 1741 August 1 1744 June 12; December 28 1745 January 23
Rae, Capt. n.d. [1740 June 16] 1740 September 8
Ritchie, John 1743 September 20
Messrs. Walter & Robert Scott, Madeira 1739 July 5
Tennant, James, Glasgow 1743 June 16
Vass, Mrs. Anne 1741 March 4
Wilson, J. 1741 March 4
Related Material
Most of the library belonging to Francis Jerdone is located in the Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary. This library contains approximately 100 books.
Separated Materials at Colonial Williamsburg
Colonial Williamsburg has five items that may prove useful to researchers. They are listed as follows:
Francis Jerdone Collection, Colonial Williamsburg Research Library, Colonial Williamsburg, Williamsburg, Virginia.
Account Book, 1751-1752.
Cargo Waste Book, 1748-1749.
Deed, from the heirs of Thomas Martin to Francis Jerdone for one thousand acres of land in Louisa (formerly Hanover) County, Virginia, 24 March 1752.
Letter from Norfolk, [Virginia], to Francis Jerdone, Mitchel's Store, Louisa County, [Virginia], 1809 January 26.
Letter from Hampton, Virginia, to uncle Francis Jerdone[?], 1803 September 29.
Separated Materials at the Library of Virginia
The Library of Virginia have multiple items that relate to Francis Jerdone and the Jerdone Family. The items listed below are an example of some of the larger collections being held at this institution, and is not meant to be a comprehensive listing. For more information see the Library of Virginia homepage:
http://www.lva.lib.va.us/
or search the archives and manuscripts at the Library of Virginia:
http://eagle.vsla.edu/bible/
Personal Papers Collection. Accession 20939. The Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia.
Balance book, 1750-1787.Items are available as photostats (negative).
This collection includes a typescript copy of a record of balances of Francis Jerdone of Louisa County, Virginia, as attorney for Buchanan and Hamilton, Merchants, of London, dated 31 December 1750, as well as estate accounts of George Pottie, dated from 1764-1787, and notations of their settlement.
Francis Jerdone Papers, 1783-1822. Accession 21466. Personal Papers Collection, The Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia.
Francis Jerdone Papers, 1783-1822.Items are available as photostats (negative).
Papers, 1783-1822, of Francis Jerdone (1756-1841) of Louisa County, Virginia, consisting of correspondence from Dr. Robert B. Honeyman (1752-1822) of Hanover County, Virginia, concerning the health and medical treatment of Jerdone's family and slaves.
Jerdone Family Papers, 1749-1873. Accession 20415. Personal Papers Collection, The Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia.
Jerdone Family Papers, 1749-1873. Items are available in microform format.
This accession includes a typescript of the accounts of Francis Jerdone of Louisa County, with a number of individuals. There is also a slave birth register, tax list, and crop accounts.
Jerdone Family Papers, 1762-1866. Accession 21607. Personal Papers Collection, The Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia.
Jerdone Family Papers, 1762-1866.
This collection consists of papers, 1762-1866, of the Jerdone family of Louisa, New Kent, Orange and Spotsylvania Counties, Virginia, consisting mainly of correspondence to Francis Jerdone, Jr. (1756-1841), of Louisa County from his sons, relatives, friends, and business partners regarding personal, family, and business matters.
Jerdone Family Slave Record Book, 1761-1865. Accession 20415. Personal papers collection, The Library of Virginia, Archives Branch, Richmond, Virginia.
Slave Record Book, 1761-1865.Item is available as photostats (negative).
Record of the slave births from 1761-1865, and the lists of tithables for Albemarle, Louisa, and Spotsylvania Counties for which the Jerdone Family was responsible.
Francis Jerdone, Sr. Memorandum and Account Book, 1766-1767. Accession 21659. Personal Papers Collection, The Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia.
Memorandum and Account Book, 1766-1767.
Item includes entries on business matters, loans, tobacco, and other goods. There are also numerous entries relevant to sales of slaves.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Jerdone family.
Persons:
Jerdone, Francis, 1721-1771.; Jerdone, Francis, 1756-1841.; Jerdone, Francis, b. 1802.; Jerdone, John, b. 1800.; Jerdone, William, 1805-1865.; Jett, Thomas.; John Morton Jordan & Co. (London, Eng.)
Subjects:
Agriculture--Virginia--History.; Agriculture--Southern States--History.; Farm management--Virginia--History.; Farm management--Southern States-- History.; Slavery--Virginia--History--18th century.; Slavery--Virginia--History-- 19th century.
Components List
  Series 1: Correspondence
- Correspondence, 1753-1890. (Box 1-10)
  - Letters, 1750-1779., 6 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Francis Jerdone, York [County, Virginia] to his wife Sarah [Macon] Jerdone, New Kent County, [Virginia], 12 July 1753., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Describes missing his wife while he is away; explains plans for moving his belongings; other family news.
    - Francis Jerdone, Ivy Creek, to his wife Sarah [Macon] Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 10 July 1759., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Discusses developments at the mill and filling of pond; refers to outbreak of measles; refers to "arrival of the London ships;" orders overseer to stick close to corn and send up two Negroes to court to be judged; other family news.
    - W[illiam] Holt, Hanover Court, to George Pottie, Louisa County, [Virginia], 4 October 1771., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Explains his side of debt with Francis Jerdone; claims he doesn't owe as much as was originally stated.
    - John Jerdone, Academy near the Road, Islington, [England] to his mother, Sarah Jerdone, Louisa County, Virginia, 21 March 1777., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Reports on relations in England and Scotland; expresses wish that dispute between mother and daughter be resolved; reports on his studies; other family news.
    - George F. Norton, London [England], to Francis Jerdone, Jedburgh, [Scotland], 25 February 1779., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Speaks of various accounts he has taken care of for Francis Jerdone: has paid mother's balance, paid "J. N." and brother's schooling bill; money is scarce and has £1100 worth of tobacco unsold; other news.
    - James Withers, London [England], to Francis Jerdone, Jedburgh, North Britain [Scotland], 13 August 1779., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Explains that had drawn an account five days over allowed time; person to whom payment was remitted returned payment; Mr. Clay has arrived in Williamsburg; other family news.
  - Letters, 1780-1789., 104 items. (Box 1-2)
    - Tho[mas] Mitchell, n.p., to Francis Jerdone. n.p., [October 1781?]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Sends list of articles sent by "Minnie"; cotton not up yet; has sent cheeses to four people [brothers-in-law?]; has been working from "sunrise to sunsete"[sic] and will have to wait until Christmas to see them; other news.
    - W[illia]m Douglass, Providence Forge, [Virginia], to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 18 April 1782., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Will see Mr. Holt around the 4th of May who will inform Jerdone of the answer given to unspecified business proposition; Douglass has similar view as Jerdone on this proposition; feels hurt by this similar ambition; expects visit from Mr. Pottie.
    - W[illia]m Douglass, Providence Forge, [Virginia], to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, 30 August 1782., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Sketches out business affair between himself and Mr. Holt; had wished to send him a saddle but too expensive; having problems with slaves; wishes an overseer; asks Jerdone to keep his eyes open for one; other family news.
      See also medium oversize file.